Pull over.
At the intersection ahead,
just pull over there.
Okay.
Let me drive you inside.
No need.
It's hard to turn around inside.
Just leave straight from there.
Chief, take care on your way home.
Okay.
Drive safe.
Go on.
[Born with Luck]
[Episode 3]
Who changed the plan for tonight?
What's wrong?
It used to be inspections
in the downtown area.
Now it's citywide checkpoints.
All the police forces have been deployed.
What are they trying to do?
Bring up the scene.
[August 23, 2012]
[Smart Traffic Service Platform]
[Sanjiangkou Police Station]
Chief Zhang,
look for yourself.
[Smart Traffic Service Platform]
[Sanjiangkou Police Station]
[Wenjing Road] [Sujiang Road]
[Sanjiang Road]
Whose idea was this?
Mine.
It was my idea.
I thought the previous plan
only targeted
key areas and roads.
Drunk drivers
are drunk, not stupid.
They can take a detour.
The current plan
is a bit messy,
but the effect is quite obvious.
Chief Zhang,
the previous plan
was based on our manpower.
Your plan
is very good.
But there is a problem now.
Many people are stuck on the road
and can't go home.
How do we solve it?
The answer is in the question.
I got it.
This is the effect Chief Zhang wants.
Even if it causes
a day of hardship,
we must serve a warning
and deter drunk drivers.
This way, they won't dare to
risk it again.
Captain Wang, what do you think?
I...
My opinion doesn't matter.
You're the boss.
As they say,
"Tears for your family,
and blood for yourself."
We must take this seriously.
We might even find out
something else.
Ninety.
Ninety-one.
Ninety-two.
Ninety-three.
Ninety-four.
N-Ninety-five.
N-Ninety-six.
Ninety-seven.
Ninety-eight.
Ninety-nine.
One hundred.
♪ The stars twinkle, the moon curves ♪
Drive safe!
♪ The breeze blows the willow tree tips ♪
Bro.
Brake.
Don't worry.
Hey,
brake.
Brake!
I can't brake!
Brake, bro!
Piece of junk.
Selling us this scrapped car
for 25,000.
It's practically a crime.
What's wrong with a crime?
Committing crimes is our job.
Others can look down on us.
But we must never
look down on ourselves.
Supply and demand dictate the price.
In recent years, the police
have cracked down hard on illegal cars.
It's hard now to bypass procedures
and buy an illegal car
with all the papers.
This junk is only worth 5,000.
The other 20,000 is for the documents.
But this money must be spent.
Otherwise, if the police
find our car in the future
and track it down,
won't they discover
that we bought it?
We need to begin with the end in mind.
Our main goal in coming to Sanjiangkou
is ultimately
to rob a corrupt official.
We can't skimp on the necessary
preliminary preparations.
Right now,
we're just counting on
robbing a big corrupt official
to break even.
I thought
the gold we robbed
and that God of Wealth statue
would be worth at least
a million.
That bastard Zheng
only gave us 80,000.
He told us that right now,
stolen goods are hard to launder.
Does gold need to be laundered?
Just melt it down and it's done!
He'd better hope I don't run into him.
If I do, I'll definitely kill him.
The money he scammed from us
will return doubled
before long.
After we rob the corrupt official,
everything other than cash
still needs to be
brought to Zheng to be liquidated.
Then we'll take him out
and get our stuff back.
This way, we get the money
and still have the stuff.
Doesn't that double the value?
That makes sense.
Then,
we'll find another collector next time,
and do exactly the same thing.
We give him the stuff,
get the money,
then go back, take him out,
and get the stuff back.
Doesn't that double it again?
Bro,
it'll be like we robbed
the corrupt official four times.
Your math is excellent.
No wonder you can't find a proper job.
Why don't we just take out
that bastard who just sold us the car,
and be done with it, bro?
You really are excellent.
Hey, man.
Did I just give you 20,000
or 25,000?
No.
Why do I still have 5,000 left here?
Okay, come and get it.
We haven't gone far.
Go past the first traffic light,
keep going,
and turn right at the fork.
Okay, see you in a bit.
♪ Bunny, bunny, bunny, bunny,
bunny, bunny ♪
♪ Love you, love you, love you ♪
♪ Bunny, bunny, bunny, bunny,
bunny, bunny ♪
♪ Love you, love you, love you ♪
This is a perfect place for murder.
I'm here.
Where are you?
Walk inside.
By the river.
Wait a minute.
Murder!
How does he know
about the murder?
Murder!
He sees the future?
Run!
Chief Qi.
Where is it?
Over there.
Who's that?
A car dealer.
You reported the case, right?
He's a used car dealer.
Ye was killed last night.
His transaction was scheduled
for this morning.
The time doesn't add up.
He shouldn't be the killer.
You must investigate it thoroughly.
Understood.
Chen!
Chief Qi,
evidence collection is complete.
You can come over.
You guys carry on.
Who has a cigarette?
Got a cigarette?
Do any of you have a cigarette?
Chief Qi, didn't you quit?
I asked who has a cigarette!
I have some here.
Bro.
He has a sharp tongue but a soft heart.
You must have
experienced this too.
He's a...
A straightforward person.
Come.
We might
not have become good friends,
but we should've been good partners.
Don't take it to heart.
He was like this to everyone.
Actually, he was the hardest on himself.
He told me
many times to my face.
If he grew old
and had tubes going in and out of him,
lying in a hospital bed,
he wouldn't accept dying like that.
For him, the most perfect way to die
would be
cracking the hardest case
in the world,
and catching
the most cunning criminal.
Then he would laugh out loud,
and pass away instantly.
Passed away instantly.
He shall grow not old,
as we that are left grow old.
Age
shall not weary him.
At the going down of the sun
and in the morning,
we will remember him.
Take him away.
Gently.
Wait a moment.
Come.
Yi'ang,
you're new,
but you are the deputy director
of the CID.
You have to do everything you can,
search high and low,
to bring the killer to justice.
I will do my best.
Chief Qi.
I found this
under Ye's body.
What is it?
A name is written on it.
A name?
It is highly likely that Ye left
the killer's name.
What is it?
[Yi'ang]
Your name.
He...
He didn't write Zhang Yi'ang.
And right now,
we can't be sure
if this is Ye's handwriting.
Chief Qi,
whether it's Ye's handwriting
still needs to be authenticated.
Could the killer have written it
to frame you?
Chen,
what is Ye's estimated time of death?
Preliminary assessment
is that it was between
11 P.M. and midnight
last night.
Where were you at this time?
Last night, Li Qian drove me
at 10:30 P.M.
from work
to my home.
Chief, it's very convenient
to take a taxi.
Why spend that money?
You drive me home,
then take my car.
Don't waste money.
Save up when you can.
That's correct.
And then?
Then I used my phone at home
to order takeout
from Wangzuo Malaban.
It was delivered at 11:30 P.M.
I went to sleep after eating.
Verify this.
Yes, sir.
Don't rush.
Make sure to figure
everything out.
Yes, sir.
[Loyalty]
Why would my name be written?
Even if Ye had an issue with me,
he shouldn't hold onto internal conflicts
at a time like this.
It indeed doesn't make sense.
You just arrived in Sanjiangkou.
Speaking of internal conflicts,
you're the one benefiting,
so you have no motive for the crime.
If you were the one lying there,
and wrote Captain Ye's name,
that would actually be quite logical.
I...
I'm just speculating, hypothetically.
No offense.
None taken.
I kind of wish
I was the one lying there,
and you all were here speculating
about what happened to me.
Chief!
What is it?
The person who delivered
your food yesterday has been found.
Found?
Yes.
You really found them?
Are you sure?
Yes.
Thank you, Song.
It's my job.
I...
Thank you.
[Police]
Good.
Good. I'm glad it's found.
[Police]
I'm fine here.
You can go back to work.
I'll contact that person now
to come to the station for a statement.
Thank you.
Chief.
We found the witness
who delivered your meal.
You're cleared of suspicion now, right?
Will we still look into
Captain Ye's case?
Though I am in the clutch
of circumstance,
I thank whatever gods may be
for my unconquerable soul.
I understand.
You mean
you want to investigate to the end.
How did you
get that meaning?
Weren't you just reciting
William Ernest Henley's poem?
I remember the next lines are:
Under the bludgeonings of chance,
my head is bloody, but unbowed.
My body is battered,
my soul is bruised,
but I am unafraid.
Those are the lines.
Chief, let's analyze this.
Captain Ye
didn't have this accident
at any other time.
He was murdered
right when you took office.
And you clearly came down here
with the task of investigating
Chief Lu's case.
Is it possible
that Captain Ye's murder
is connected to Chief Lu's case?
That's a very bold analysis.
But I suggest
we shouldn't be so bold right now.
Chief,
we need to go through
all the criminal cases handled
in the year before Chief Lu died,
one by one,
to see if there are any clues.
What do you think?
I think...
we can.
We can take a look.
It's just that I have a lot
on my plate right now.
Don't worry about it. I'll go check.
Thank you for your efforts.
At such a young age,
why do you read so much poetry?
[Reason for borrowing: case investigation]
[Name: Ye Jian]
[Criminal Investigation File]
All filled out?
Captain Ye
also came to review files yesterday?
Yes.
What kind of cases were they?
Cases Chief Lu was involved in
the year before he passed away.
They're all right here.
Thanks.
Li Qian.
I was looking for you.
What's wrong, Chief Qi?
Yi'ang,
come, have a seat.
The trace inspection results are out.
The small stone used for writing
only had
Ye's blood and fingerprints on it.
Around the body,
there were no biological traces
of anyone else.
So,
your name
could only have been written by Ye himself
right before he died.
There's another thing.
Why did you
order food from Wangzuo Malaban?
That place is
seven or eight kilometers away
from where you live.
It tastes good.
Well... what's wrong?
Chief Zhang,
the woman who delivered your food,
Jiang Ying,
has gone missing.
Missing?
After the police went to the restaurant
and confirmed with her,
I wanted her to come to the bureau
so we could ask a few questions.
But when I called her,
her phone was already turned off.
Missing?
What,
are you suspecting that I
arranged for...
a fake witness?
Some comrades here
might have some feelings against me,
or even
be unwilling to cooperate with my work.
I can understand that.
But everything
has its limits, doesn't it?
If someone is
intentionally spreading rumors
to frame me,
I cannot forgive that.
What really makes us suspicious
is her testimony.
Li Qian.
Chief Zhang,
last night,
I only dropped you off
at the intersection near your house.
Whether you actually went home or not,
I...
truly don't know.
Chief Zhang.
After that,
you gave Ye a call,
right?
Yes,
I did call him.
Can I see your phone?
At the time, why didn't you mention
[Call Record] [Ye Jian]
this detail?
I forgot.
I really just forgot.
I made that call to Ye
to have a talk with him.
Talk about what?
I just wanted to talk.
Between us,
there's no real conflict.
We still have to
work together in the future.
I wanted to treat him to a meal.
Treat him to a meal
or have a talk?
Chief Qi, what does this mean?
Everyone just wants to understand
the situation more clearly.
Yi'ang,
where are you going?
I don't think you should
get involved in this case, okay?
I'll definitely stay out of the case.
I need to find that delivery worker.
Right now, only she can prove
that I'm innocent.
Is that okay?
Don't just stand there.
Go help look.
[Police]
Chief.
Let me do it.
Chief,
where are we going now?
Sorry, Song Xing.
Chief, what's wrong?
I shouldn't have said that
to you upstairs just now.
You don't need to apologize.
You don't need to apologize
no matter how you scold or hit me.
As police,
we should
doubt the doubt of the doubt.
I said that myself.
You are right
to suspect me.
Chief.
Since I became a policeman,
in every meeting,
I have been thinking actively
and eager to speak.
I've made at least
hundreds of suggestions.
But Captain Ye and the others
have never accepted them.
At the very beginning,
they still let me speak.
Now,
they don't even let me talk in meetings.
I have no idea
why they treat me like this.
But you,
you're different.
About the joint DUI operation,
I just went to you
with the mindset of
giving it a try.
I didn't expect you to accept it
without me even explaining.
Later,
when such a big thing happened,
you still said I was right
and that I helped you.
What is appreciation?
This is appreciation.
Chief,
when you said that,
I made up my mind.
I will follow you for the rest of my life.
Xing,
in my life,
I have basically never misjudged anyone.
Chief,
when Chief Qi asked me,
of course I had to tell the truth.
I did only drop you off
at the intersection that day.
But for this matter,
you just need to prove that
it was impossible
for you to be at the scene then.
Then it'll be over.
You are a veteran detective.
So smart and experienced.
For you,
this must be very easy.
I am not
a show-off.
Coming to Sanjiangkou,
I should keep a lower profile.
Now you are forcing me
to rush to the front line.
What should I do?
Show off my skills to our comrades?
-Just show us.
We really want to see it.
Xing, stop driving in circles.
I'm a little carsick.
No,
Chief.
It's not that I'm driving in circles.
You haven't told me
where we are going.
Where are we going?
Wait a minute. I'm a little carsick.
Okay.
We found Jiang Ying's address.
Follow me.
Sir,
what are you doing? Open the door.
Going out?
What do you think?
This gate...
[Yingzi General Store]
Police!
Is anyone there?
How's the situation?
Chief.
I don't think there's anyone inside.
Did you call them?
Both their phones are turned off.
Should we
break the door open now?
Chief Zhang is going to
break the door open.
That's against protocol.
They aren't criminals.
We don't have a warrant.
On what grounds can we break in?
Who will take the blame
if something happens?
Chief Qi said...
I heard him. I heard it all.
Look.
When Captain Ye had his accident,
this woman delivered food to me.
Right?
Now both of them have run away.
Don't you find that suspicious?
Suspicious.
So do you agree to break in?
I agree it's suspicious.
But we need a warrant to force the door.
With no warrant and no evidence,
how can we break in?
The evidence is inside.
If I don't break in,
how can I get the evidence?
We can't break in without evidence.
[Yingzi General Store]
Chief Zhang has no solutions.
He's helpless.
I know
I will be neglected
in some corner of the world.
The last remaining
glimmer of light,
at the end of life,
will flicker
and be extinguished.
It's time
for Chief Zhang's poetry recitation.
Extinguished.
Chief Zhang!
This is the landlord.
Hello.
Ma'am,
Jiang Ying, who lives here,
is an important witness.
Do you agree to let us
to break the door open and investigate?
No.
Why do you need to break in?
I have a key.
Thank you, ma'am.
Come on, turn on the body cams.
Hurry up.
Turn it on.
[Police]
Who is the person
living with Jiang Ying?
It's Jiang Ying's husband.
I think his surname is Li.
When they left,
did they tell you?
They didn't say anything.
What could that couple have done?
That man wouldn't even
dare to kill a chicken.
The bedroom's in there?
Yes.
Chief Zhang.
Hold this for me.
The woman's height is between 1.60
and 1.62 meters.
She has a well-proportioned figure,
weighs no more than 50 kilograms,
and dresses neatly.
She has fair skin
and chestnut hair.
Her footsteps?
Light and fast.
She speaks clearly and briskly.
What about the man?
I don't know about the man.
How do you know about the woman?
The woman delivered food to me.
I've seen her.
Here.
Notify everyone immediately.
Mobilize all police forces
from surrounding towns
and police stations.
Secure the bus and train stations,
and all major entrances
and exits of the city.
Launch a citywide manhunt immediately.
Tonight,
we must catch them
in Sanjiangkou.
[Sanjiangkou Transportation Center]
[Please keep one meter away]
Let's go.
A guy over there keeps looking at me.
Could he be a cop?